{
  "theme": [
    {
      "Questions": {
        "theme": [
          {
            "Question": "What is the title of Mark Twain's autobiography?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Life on the Mississippi",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "The Adventures of Tom Sawyer",
              "The Prince and the Pauper",
              "Huckleberry Finn"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Mark Twain's 'Life on the Mississippi' is an autobiographical account of his experiences as a steamboat pilot on the Mississippi River, offering insightful anecdotes about the era and culture of the time."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who authored the memoir 'In the Country of Men'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Hisham Matar",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Maya Angelou",
              "Tara Westover",
              "Jeanette Walls"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Hisham Matar's 'In the Country of Men' depicts his childhood experiences in Libya during the oppressive Gaddafi regime and the impact of political turmoil on family life."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which memoir chronicles Malala Yousafzai's fight for education?",
            "TrueAnswer": "I Am Malala",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Educated",
              "The Glass Castle",
              "A Long Way Gone"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Malala Yousafzai's 'I Am Malala' recounts her courageous advocacy for female education in Pakistan and surviving a targeted assassination attempt by the Taliban."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who wrote the autobiographical novel 'Becoming'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Michelle Obama",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Tina Fey",
              "Marie Kondo",
              "Anthony Bourdain"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Michelle Obama's 'Becoming' offers a captivating glimpse into her life, from her roots in Chicago to her transformative years as the First Lady of the United States."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the title of Trevor Noah's autobiography?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Born a Crime",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "The Glass Castle",
              "Educated",
              "Wild"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Trevor Noah's 'Born a Crime' illuminates his upbringing in apartheid-era South Africa, navigating the complexities of race, identity, and survival with humor and resilience."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who wrote 'Angela's Ashes', an acclaimed memoir set in Ireland?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Frank McCourt",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "David Sedaris",
              "Jeannette Walls",
              "Maya Angelou"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Frank McCourt's 'Angela's Ashes' portrays his impoverished childhood in Limerick, Ireland, and the enduring spirit that emerged from the adversities of his upbringing."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What memoir delves into the culinary world of Anthony Bourdain?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Kitchen Confidential",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Bossypants",
              "Born a Crime",
              "In the Country of Men"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Anthony Bourdain's 'Kitchen Confidential' provides an unfiltered behind-the-scenes exploration of the restaurant industry, revealing its vibrant, chaotic, and often unseen aspects."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who penned the memoir 'The Year of Magical Thinking'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Joan Didion",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie",
              "Maya Angelou",
              "Tara Westover"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Joan Didion's 'The Year of Magical Thinking' intertwines grief and reflection, chronicling the aftermath of the sudden loss of her husband and navigating the disorienting landscape of bereavement."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which memoir details Elie Wiesel's experiences during the Holocaust?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Night",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Long Walk to Freedom",
              "A Long Way Gone",
              "The Glass Castle"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Elie Wiesel's 'Night' is a haunting recollection of his time in Auschwitz and Buchenwald, bearing witness to the atrocities of the Holocaust and the enduring human spirit."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who chronicled her radical self-discovery in 'Wild'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Cheryl Strayed",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Roxane Gay",
              "Tara Westover",
              "Hanya Yanagihara"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Cheryl Strayed's 'Wild' captures her transformative solo hike on the Pacific Crest Trail, navigating profound personal loss and finding strength and redemption in nature's unforgiving terrain."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the title of Nelson Mandela's memoir?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Long Walk to Freedom",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Dreams from My Father",
              "The Year of Magical Thinking",
              "Born a Crime"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Nelson Mandela's 'Long Walk to Freedom' details his lifelong commitment to justice, freedom, and equality in the face of apartheid, reflecting his extraordinary resilience and leadership."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who penned the memoir 'Educated'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Tara Westover",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Malala Yousafzai",
              "Michelle Obama",
              "Anthony Bourdain"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Tara Westover's 'Educated' recounts her journey from a restrictive childhood in rural Idaho to pursuing higher education, navigating family complexities and forging her own path to independence."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which memoir details Jeannette Walls' upbringing in a dysfunctional family?",
            "TrueAnswer": "The Glass Castle",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "In the Country of Men",
              "Wild",
              "Kitchen Confidential"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Jeannette Walls' 'The Glass Castle' vividly portrays her tumultuous childhood marked by poverty, family dynamics, and her ultimate quest for resilience and independence."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who wrote the memoir 'Dreams from My Father'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Barack Obama",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Trevor Noah",
              "Cheryl Strayed",
              "Frank McCourt"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Barack Obama's 'Dreams from My Father' intricately explores his multiracial heritage, familial complexities, and the profound journey of self-discovery that shaped his identity and aspirations."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What memoir details the plight of a boy during the Sierra Leone Civil War?",
            "TrueAnswer": "A Long Way Gone",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Kitchen Confidential",
              "In the Country of Men",
              "The Year of Magical Thinking"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Ishmael Beah's 'A Long Way Gone' grippingly narrates his harrowing experiences as a child soldier, reflecting the resilience, trauma, and quest for redemption amidst the ravages of war."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who chronicled her journey of resilience in 'The Diary of a Young Girl'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Anne Frank",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Mary Karr",
              "Maya Angelou",
              "Joan Didion"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Anne Frank's 'The Diary of a Young Girl' presents her unwavering spirit amidst the horrors of the Holocaust, capturing the resilience of the human soul in the face of adversity and intolerance."
          },
          {
            "Question": "What is the title of Maya Angelou's autobiographical series?",
            "TrueAnswer": "I Know Why the Caged Bird Sings",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Life on the Mississippi",
              "Long Walk to Freedom",
              "Born a Crime"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Maya Angelou's 'I Know Why the Caged Bird Sings' unveils the profound challenges and triumphs of her early life, portraying her indomitable spirit and quest for self-discovery amidst adversity and prejudice."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who penned the memoir 'Running with Scissors'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Augusten Burroughs",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Michelle Obama",
              "Angela Davis",
              "Cheryl Strayed"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Augusten Burroughs' 'Running with Scissors' candidly portrays his unconventional upbringing and tumultuous family dynamics, offering an unflinching exploration of resilience and survival amid dysfunction."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Which memoir details the author's journey through addiction and recovery?",
            "TrueAnswer": "The Liars' Club",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "A Long Way Gone",
              "Kitchen Confidential",
              "The Diary of a Young Girl"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Mary Karr's 'The Liars' Club' delves into her turbulent upbringing and struggles with alcoholism while depicting the transformative nature of resilience, forgiveness, and healing."
          },
          {
            "Question": "Who wrote the memoir 'The Girl with Seven Names'?",
            "TrueAnswer": "Hyeonseo Lee",
            "FalseAnswer": [
              "Nelson Mandela",
              "Trevor Noah",
              "Elie Wiesel"
            ],
            "Explanation": "Hyeonseo Lee's 'The Girl with Seven Names' narrates her escape from North Korea and the challenges of rebuilding a new identity while navigating the complexities of freedom and assimilation."
          }
        ]
      }
    }
  ]
}